Guide to the Gay & Lesbian Advocates & Defenders Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1975-1999; Accession 2015-M-014
  - Molinari: Risk data produced, 1989 November (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Molinari: Risk data produced, 1989 November (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Molinari: Extra risk documents, 1989 November (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Molinari: Documents relied upon in expert report, 1995 March (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Molinari: deposition transcript, 1995 August (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Molinari: Deposition exhibits, Undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Molinari: Deposition notes/outlines, Undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Molinari: Expert report, 1995 April (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Molinari: Supplemental export reports, 1995 June (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Molinari: ADA demographics, 1993-1995 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Molinari: Documents produced Table of contents 1-10, 1989-1995 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Molinari: Documents produced Table of contents 11-19, 1989-1995 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Molinari: Curriculum Vitae, Undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Molinari: Publications in Curriculum Vitae, 1984-1995 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 4 bound items, 1997 October (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 8 bound items, 1997 October (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 4 bound items, 1997 October (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 4 bound items, 1997 October (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 5 bound items, 1997-1998 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 5 photocopied items, 1997 October (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 5 photocopied items, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 7 bound items, 1998 October (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 1 bound item, 1998 October (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 1 bound item, 1998 October (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 7 photocopied items, 1998 October (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Certiorari brief - 4 photocopied items, 1998 October (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - USDOJ: US' motion and memo. for summary judgment, 1995 September (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - MHRC: Exhibit 2: " Accessibility requirements" (Int. reply memo), 1994 July (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - MHRC: Exhibit 3: Employment regulations of the Maine Human Rights Commission, 1988 May (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - MHRC: Exhibit 4: Public accommodation regulations, 1987 March (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - MHRC: Exhibit 4:Supplemental expert report of John A. Molinari, PH.D, 1995 June (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - MHRC: Plaintiff commission's request for oral argument, 1995 September (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - MHRC: "Accessibility requirements for public accommodations and places of employment, Undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Defendant's motion for summary judgment under the ADA and MHRA …….., 1995 March (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Summary judgment burden of proof issue, 1995 September (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Summary judgment burden of proof issue, 1998 September (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - U.S. DOJ: Statement of uncontested facts in support of it's motion for summary judgment, 1995 August (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - United States' Opposition to defendant's motion for summary judgment, 1995 October (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Extra copies of pleadings, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Supreme court - 4 bound items, 1997 October (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Supreme court - 8 bound items, 1997 October (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Supreme court - 3 bound items, 1997 October (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Supreme court - 8 photocopied items, 1997 October (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Supreme court - 1 photocopied item, 1997 October (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, Undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1998-2000 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1996 April (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1996 September (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1998 August (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1998 September (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1998 September (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1998 September (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Remand Briefs, 1998 September (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Reply brief disk (no disk in folder), 1998 October (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Brief of the Amicus Curiae, 1997 October (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Petitioner's Supplemental Brief, 1998 October (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - First circuit briefs, 1995 July (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - First circuit briefs, 1996 April (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - First circuit briefs, 1996 July (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - First circuit briefs, 1996 September0 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - First circuit briefs, 1996 September0 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - First circuit briefs, 1997 March (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - First circuit briefs, Undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: On Remand, 1998 June (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: On Remand, 1998 September (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: On Remand, 1998 September 29 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: On Remand, 1998 September 29 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: On Remand, Undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Appeals, 1996 July (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Appeals, 1996 September (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Appeals, 1997 March (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Appeals, Undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Questions and answers, Undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Decisions, 1997-1998 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Abbott v. Bragdon: Transcript of summary judgment, 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Hearing transcript, 1996 April (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Summary judgment: Notes, Undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Summary judgment Oral argument notes, Undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Report of telephone conference of counsel, 1995 November (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - MCRC: Motion for summary judgment, 1995 September (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - MHRC: Intervenor commission memorandum for summary judgment, 1995 September (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - MHRC: Intervenor commission reply memorandum, 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - MHRC: Statement of material facts, 1995 September (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - MHRC: Exhibit 1: Affidavit of Patricia E. Ryan (int. reply memo), 1995 September (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Declaration of Marianos, D.D.S., etc. [U.S. D.O.J. expert], 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - United States reply memo on summary judgment, 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - United States opposition to Defendant's motion for summary judgment, 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Bragdon: MCRC's memorandum in opposition to defendant's summary judgment motion, 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Bragdon: Dept. of Justice exhibits to it's opposition to def.'s summary judgment motion, 1995 October (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Deposition of Sidney Abbott, 1995 May (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Defendant's rule 19 statement of undisputed material facts, 1995 September (Box 48, Folder 19)
- Additional material, 1984-2016; 2000-2007; Accession 2017-M-035
  This accession documents three major projects GLAD worked on from 2000 to 2007. Cote-Whitacre, et al v. Department of Public Health ruled on recognition of same-sex marriages performed in Massachusetts by other states. The case files include pleadings, case documents, related research, and amicus curiae briefs. These cover all stages of Cote-Whitacre, et al and its related case, also filed by GLAD, Johnstone, et al v. Thomas O'Reilly. Nancy Walsh's claim to the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001 for her domestic partner, Carol Flyzik, includes documentation pertaining to their domestic partnership; Flyzik's personal records; correspondence with GLAD, the law firm Kreindler and Kreindler, and the families of Walsh and Flyzik; applications to the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001; and court documents. There are also drafts and newspaper clippings relating to H. 0847, the Vermont state bill that created civil unions for same-sex couples. Finally, there are publicity materials for different GLAD fundraising events from 1984 to 2016, including fliers and posters.
  The accession is arranged under four headings: Cote-Whitacre, et al v. Department of Health case files, Walsh case files, Vermont civil union legislation, and GLAD event publicity materials. Within these headings, materials are arranged as received from the donor.
  - Cote-Whitacre, et al v. Department of Public Health case files
    - Compiled case documents
      - Volume I, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
      - Volume II, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4-5, Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Volume III, 2005-2007 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
      - Appendix
        - Volume I, Circa 2004 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
        - Volume II, Circa 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Cote-Whitacre, et al Superior Court files
      - Worcester procedures, 2004-05-18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Public records request, 2004-04-26 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Attorney General cease and desist letter, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Springfield letter to Attorney General, 2004-05-26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Cambridge counsel letter to City Manager, 2003-11-24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Kopelman and Paige letter to Fall River, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Somerville letter to Attorney General, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Clerks v. Reilly drafts, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Responses of other states to Romney, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Pleadings
        - Verifications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Drafts, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - Johnstone v. Reilly amended complaint, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Preliminary injunction memorandum, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Attorney General's opposition, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Johnstone, et al v. Thomas O'Reilly Superior Court files
      - Volume I, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      - Volume II, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Clerks' supplemental index, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Judge Ball decision on motion for preliminary injunction, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Appeal documents, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7, Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Affidavits of town and city clerks, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Appendix to clerks' affidavits, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cote-Whitacre, et al Appeals Court files
      - Application for direct appellate review, 2004-08-18 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Copies 2, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Judge Ball decision on motion for preliminary injunction, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Copies, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Hearing transcript, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Briefing on New York, 2004-2007 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - New York, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
      - Hernandez v. Robles - New York, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
      - Addendum to Hernandez amicus, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - New Jersey, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Appeal brief and reply - plaintiffs, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Clerk briefs, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 49 page reply, 2005-07-29 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Attorney General application - direct appellate review, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Attorney General brief, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
      - Attorney General amicus briefs, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Goodridge - opinion of Justices, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Judge Ball decision, 2004-08 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Notes for argument, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Drafting notes to self, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Notes, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - BBA presentation, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Massachusetts Lesbian & Gay Bar Association (MLGBA) summary, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - 1913 amicus, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
      - Flynn and Doyle v. Cities, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Cote-Whitacre, et al Supreme Court files
      - Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Hearing notices, 2005-2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Plaintiffs and appellants clerks brief, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Brief of plaintiffs - appellants, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Reply brief
        - Plaintiffs, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - Plaintiffs - appellants (unbound), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - Plaintiffs - appellants (clerks), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - Clerks - 20 pages (unbound), 2005 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Addendum to Hale and Dorr conflicts brief (New York comptroller letter), 2004 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Amicus briefs - constitutional law professors, family law professors, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Amici for couples: civil rights, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Plaintiffs: notices of intention (copies), 2004 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Amicus briefs, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Brief of appellees, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Opposing amici: Shields and Flynn, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Opposing amici: Goverman, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Record appendix, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
      - Provincetown - notices of intention, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Romney 10, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Draft record appendix
        - Volume I, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Volume II, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
      - Romney administration memoranda to clerks regarding Supreme Judicial Court ruling, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Instructions to clerks, Spring 2004 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Amended and final New York judgment, 2004-2007 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Rhode Island judgment, 2000-09-29 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - New York decision, 2007-05 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Supreme Judicial Court - annotated, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Proposed judgment, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Supreme Judicial Court preliminary injunction decision, 2006-03-30 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - New York memorandum - remand, 2007-04-11 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Rhode Island briefing on remand, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Rhode Island oral argument notes, Circa 2006 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Goodridge trial court - Connolly, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - 1913 law - history of non-enforcement Massachusetts Freedom of Information Act response, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Recording research, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - New York recognition, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - New York press, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Repeal of 1913 law, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - New Jersey prohibition, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Research
      - Department of Public Health records search, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Public records - reverse evasion, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Public records requests - 1913, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - 1913 enforcement - public records request, 1986-2004 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
      - Void and voidable marriages, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
      - Kindregan and Inker - void and voidable, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Gould v. Gould, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Void - 11, 1929; 2004 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Compiled research for filings, 1912-2004 (Box 12, Folder 9, Box 13, Folder 1-3)
      - Pleadings
        - Preliminary injunction reply brief, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Defendants' sur-reply, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Superior Court preliminary injunction ruling, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Flynn and Shields intervention, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Superior Court preliminary injunction ruling, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - Privileges and immunities brief, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - Hearing notes and transcript, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 10)
        - Argument notes, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Reverse evasions materials
        - Uniform State Laws Marriage Evasion Act history, 1911-1913 (Box 13, Folder 12)
        - General, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
        - Massachusetts Evasion Act legislative history, 1912-1913 (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Materials on st 1913 c 360 from archives, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Other states, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - Legislative history, 1912-1913 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Goodridge: reverse evasion statute - memoranda and notes, 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
        - Massachusetts American Bar Association research project, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - Case law, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Right to travel cases - Massachusetts, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Privileges and immunities - Massachusetts case law, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Privileges and immunities articles, 1999-2004 (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Right to travel, 1999-2004 (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Residence, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Massachusetts practice series, "The Validity of Marriage", Circa 1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - Cases in registration section, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
        - Discriminatory enforcement, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - State residency requirements, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 6)
        - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) materials, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - Invidious intent, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Amicus briefs, Circa 2004 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Massachusetts residency requirements, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
  - Walsh case files
    - Financial documents as evidence of domestic partnership, 1998-2003 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Kreindler & Kreindler documents, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Kreindler & Kreindler background information, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Memorandum in support of Peggy Neff's claim to fund, Circa 2002 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Application for copy of death record, 2002-03 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - New York State Crime Victims Board claim application, Circa 2001 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Death certificate of Carol Flyzik, 2002-04-11 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Explanation of process for computing presumed economic loss, 1998-2002 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Compensation fund frequently asked questions, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Compensation forms, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Federal register: September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001; interim final rule, 2001-12-21 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Kreindler & Kreindler retainer agreement and case preparation documents, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Nancy Walsh, draft narrative/brief to accompany Victim Compensation Fund application, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
    - Copies of financial records, 1998-2003 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Carol Flyzik documents, 1961-2003 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Retainer agreement, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Stipulation and agreement, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Uniform appraisal report, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Settlement and statement, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Nancy Walsh filings, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - New York State Criminal Victims Board claim application, Circa 2001 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Case notes and related correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Original documents, 1995-2003 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Application for copy of death record, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Death certificate of Carol Flyzik, 2002-04-11 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Memorandum in support of Peggy Neff's claim to fund, Circa 2002 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Compensation forms, Circa 2002 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Compensation Fund frequently asked questions, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Final federal regulations, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Claim to the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund, 1995-2003 (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
  - Vermont civil union legislation
    - Bill tracking, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - Text of civil union laws, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Vermont updates, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - " 'Civil Unions': Where Vermont is Leading the Country", 2000 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Press clippings, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 7-9, Box 19, Folder 1)
  - GLAD events publicity material
    - Event fliers, 1984-2016 (Box 19, Folder 2-5, Box 20, Folder 1-5, Box 21, Folder 1-3, Box 22, Folder 1)